// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Number of primitive data types in java are?",
    answer: "8",
    options: [
      "6",
      "7",
      "8",
      "5"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What is the size of float and double in java?",
    answer: "32 and 64",
    options: [
      "32 and 64",
      "32 and 32",
      "64 and 64",
      "64 and 32"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Automatic type conversion is possible in which of the following cases?",
    answer: "Int to long",
    options: [
      "Byte to int",
      "Int to long",
      "Int to byte",
      "Short to int"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following option leads to the portability and security of java?",
    answer: "Bytecode is executed by JVM",
    options: [
      "Dynamic binding between objects",
      "The applet makes the Java code secure and portable",
      "Use of exception handling",
      "Bytecode is executed by JVM"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of these literals can be contained in a float data type variable?",
    answer: "+1.7e+308",
    options: [
      "-3.4+050",
      "+1.7e+308", 
      "-3.4e+038",
      "-1.7e+308"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Out of these statements,which ones are incorrect?",
    answer: "The division operator/has comparatively higher precedence as compared to a multiplication operator",
    options: [
      "The Brackets() have the highest precedence",
      "The equal to = operator has the lowest precedence",
      "The addition operator + and the subtraction operator - have an equal precedence",
      "The division operator/has comparatively higher precedence as compared to a multiplication operator"
     ]
   }, 
     {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which is used to find and fix bugs in the Java programs?",
    answer: "JDB",
    options: [
      "JVM",
      "JRE",
      "JDB",
      "JDK"
     ]
   }, 
     {
    numb: 8,
    question: "What is the return type of the hashcode() method in the Object class?",
    answer: "int",
    options: [
      "Object",
      "int",
      "long",
      "void"
     ]
   }, 
     {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is a valid long literal?",
    answer: "0xnf029L",
    options: [
      "ABH8097",
      "L990023",
      "904423",
      "0xnf029L"
     ]
   }, 
     {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Evaluate the following Java expression,if x=3,y=5,and z=10: ++z+y-y+z+x++",
    answer: "25",
    options: [
      "24",
      "25",
      "20",
      "23"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 11,
    question: "In java arrays are",
    answer: "objects",
    options: [
      "primitive data type",
      "object references",
      "objects",
      "none of the above"
     ]
   }, 
     {
    numb: 12,
    question: "tostring() method is defined in",
    answer: "java.lang.Object",
    options: [
      "java.lang.String",
      "java.lang.Object",
      "java.lang.util",
      "none of these"
     ]
   }, 
     {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Which of the following for loop declaration is not valid?",
    answer: "for (int i=99;i>=0;i/9)",
    options: [
      "for (int i=99;i>=0;i/9)",
      "for (int i=7;i<=77;i+=7)",
      "for (int i=20;i>=2;--i)",
      "for (int i=2;i<=20;i=2*i)"
     ]
   }, 
     {
    numb: 14,
    question: "When you pass an array to a method,the method receives ",
    answer: "The reference of the array",
    options: [
      "A copy of the first element",
      "A copy of the array",
      "The length of the array",
      "The reference of the array"
     ]
   }, 
     {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Select from among the following character escape code which is not available in Java",
    answer: "\\a",
    options: [
      "\\t",
      "\\r",
      "\\a",
      "\\v"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 16,
    question: "In which memory a string is stored,when we create a string using new operator?",
    answer: "Heap memory",
    options: [
      "Stack",
      "Heap memory",
      "String memory",
      "Random storage space"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
    answer: "JDK",
    options: [
      "JRE",
      "JIT",
      "JDK",
      "JVM"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 18,
    question: "Which environment variable is used to set the java path?",
    answer: "JAVA_HOME",
    options: [
      "MAVEN_Path",
      "JavaPATH",
      "JAVA",
      "JAVA_HOME"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 19,
    question: "What is not the use of “this” keyword in Java?",
    answer: "Passing itself to the method of the same class",
    options: [
      "Referring to the instance variable when a local variable has the same name",
      "Passing itself to the method of the same class",
      "Passing itself to another method",
      "Calling another constructor in constructor chaining"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 20,
    question: "The object is created with new keyword",
    answer: "At run time",
    options: [
      "Depend on the code",
      "At Compile time",
      "At run time",
      "None of these"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 21,
    question: "A package is a collection of ",
    answer: "Classes and Interfaces",
    options: [
      "Classes and Interfaces",
      "Classes",
      "Editing tools",
      "Interfaces"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 22,
    question: "Which of the following is a superclass of every class in Java?",
    answer: "Object class",
    options: [
      "ArrayList",
      "Abstract class",
      "Object class",
      "String"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Name the keyword that makes a variable belong to a class,rather than being defined for each instance of the class ",
    answer: "static",
    options: [
      "final",
      "static",
      "abstract",
      "volatile"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 24,
    question: "In java byte,short,int and long all of these are",
    answer: "signed",
    options: [
      "signed",
      "unsigned",
      "Both of the above",
      "None of the above"
     ]
   }, 
      {
    numb: 25,
    question: "Which of the following declares an abstract method in an abstract Java class",
    answer: "public abstract void method();",
    options: [
      "public abstract method();",
      "public void abstract method();",
      "public abstract void method();",
      "public void method();"
     ]
   }, 
];